JOSEPH C. BENSON

<u>IndyJoeBRJS@gmail.com</u> • 317 – 432 – 5307 www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-c-benson • https://indyjoebr.github.io/JCBportfolio/

CAREER SUMMARY

Established contributor of systems training and administration, including software, hardware, processes, and procedural improvements. Provider of internal and external customer services and office logistics. including managing complex schedules, performing stock reconciliation, and creating standardized forms. Proven researcher and editor of documents, spreadsheets, and presentations.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Eleven Fifty Academy, Indianapolis, IN

Web Development Bootcamp (Fall 2020 – in progress)

12-week immersive learning program for Web Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project-based learning and 500+ hours of logged coding times and training. Awarded by peers: Core Value Award for Teamwork.

Ivy Tech Community College, Indianapolis, IN Certificate, Java Application Development

University of Evansville, Evansville, IN Bachelor of Science, Classical Archaeology

KEY COMPETENCIES

- Website development (full stack): HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, Node.js, Bootstrap
- Experience with Java and Android mobile app development, Database administration and design, SQL, APIs, GitHub, Python, Visual Basic, COBOL, Heroku and Firebase deployment
- Adobe Acrobat, Illustrator, Advanced knowledge of MS Office Suite
- Demonstrated written and verbal communication skills, including research, copyediting, documentation, presentations, technical writing and SOWs
- 7+ years' experience in data and administrative tasks including process improvement
- Creative, curious, analytical, self-driven, problem-solver and life-long learner

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

That's Good HR, Indianapolis, IN

08/2018 - 12/2018

Graduated: Dec 2020

Graduated: Dec 2019

Summa Cum Laude

Database Technician (Contractor); **U.S. Infrastructure Company**, Indianapolis, IN 11/2018 – 12/2018 Review and transfer of tier 2 and tier 3 customer files from proprietary CRM system to Salesforce CRM. (Contract completed)

Administrative Assistant (Contractor); **Heartland FPG**, Indianapolis, IN 08/2018 – 10/2018 Front desk assistant and office reception, managing schedules, performing stock reconciliation, and creating custom forms in Excel using VLOOKUP to auto-fill. (Contract completed)

Worked primarily in MS Office 365 (Excel, Word and Outlook).

Trained purchasing personnel on form creation in MS Excel.

Indiana State Museum, Indianapolis, IN

05/2018 - present

Research and Data Analyst (Volunteer)

- Design and creation of database of Indiana companies with corporate social responsibility (CSR) programs that support volunteer programs for Vice President, Visitor Services, Security & Volunteers.
- Digitization of archived historical documents and entry into collections database.

Covance Central Laboratory Services, Indianapolis, IN

03/2001 - 09/2017

Data Coordinator, Data Revision Center

04/2016 - 09/2017

Maintenance and revision of confidential patient data and testing results in proprietary database.

- Member of two teams organized to improve departmental SOPs by streamlining processes, improving detail in flowcharts and increasing clarity of instructions.
- Participated in multi-departmental process improvement team for review of daily database error reports and subsequent data error corrections.

Senior Administrative Assistant, Medical Affairs

03/2001 - 04/2016

Provided administrative support to Vice President, Senior Director and staff pathologists and the department of Medical Affairs by managing complex schedules, arranging travel and meetings, taking and publishing meeting minutes, and ordering supplies.

- Development and administration of efficient processes for telepathology diagnosis of multiple myeloma, resulting in an 80% reduction in turnaround time with no loss in accuracy and a scaling, volume-based shipping cost savings of \$50/day.
- Expert in several regulatory agency's permits and licenses (ex: Centers for Disease Control permit to import infectious materials) and international material transfer agreements